Vivek V H



vivekmusic19@gmail.com

+91 8590213866



linkedin.com/in/vivek-v-h-694603212

Summary

Experienced Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Highly curious and hardworking with a forward-thinking IT enthusiastic life and an Excellent portfolio.



Technical Skills

- Node.js Bootstrap Express.js Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) HTML JavaScript •React.js •jQuery •Ajax
- Java
- Python
- JavaScript
- Data structures and algorithms
- **JavaScript**
- **REST API**
- Version Control: Git
- OOP
- Django
- Redux
- Databases •MongoDB MySQL Firebase
- Deployment tools: •Heroku •GitHub •Digital Ocean droplets •Digital Ocean Spaces •Netify •Firebase

Soft Skills

- Good Communication Skill
- Good Presentation Skill

Languages

- **English**
- Malayalam
- Hindi

Programming Languages

- Java
- Python
- **JavaScript**
- С
- C++
- Dart
- GO

Projects

Drive zone[MERN Stack] (Currently working): Web application that gives car reviews, pricing and all other details of car models in India and an API on the same.

- **Gym[MERN Stack]:**Web application for your daily workouts.
- **Ecommerce application[MERN Stack]:** E commerce application.
- Social Media Application[MERN STACK]: Social media application.
- Netflix UI Clone[MERN Stack]
- OLX Clone[MERN Stack]

For more projects and code, visit my GitHub profile.

GitHub

https://github.com/Vivek-v-h

Libraries

- Express
- Next.js
- Node
- React
- Django
- Flask and a lot more......

Interests

- Machine learning and Artificial Intelligence
- Coding
- Books
- API development
- Interactive web development

Certifications

- Python pro Bootcamp Udemy
- Complete Web Development Bootcamp Udemy

Experience

Web Developer

Freelance

Jun 2021 - Present (1 year +)

I am working as a MERN Stack Developer (MongoDB Express React Node).

Python Developer

Freelance Jan 2021 - Jun 2021 (6 months) Python Developer

Education



Dr GR Public School

Higher Secondary School (plus two), Computer Science Jun 2019 - May 2021



Lourdes Matha College of Science and Technology, Kuttichal, Thiruvananthapuram

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science and Engineering Oct 2021 - Present

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the facts given above are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

Date 23-07-2022

Place: Thiruvananthapuram

Name: Vivek V H

Vivek V H - page 3